[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Yellow fever is spread by",
    "option1": "Air",
    "option2": "Water",
    "option3": "House fly",
    "option4": "Mosquito",
    "answer": "House fly"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Rh factor is present in",
    "option1": "Blood",
    "option2": "Urine",
    "option3": "Lymph",
    "option4": "Sputum",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "BCG Vaccination is injected to get immunity from",
    "option1": "Polio",
    "option2": "Cholera",
    "option3": "Small Pox",
    "option4": "Tuberculosis",
    "answer": "Tuberculosis"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The structure of double helix of DNA was described by",
    "option1": "Soha",
    "option2": "Watson and Crick",
    "option3": "Fleming",
    "option4": "Hawking",
    "answer": "Watson and Crick"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which among the following helps in circulation of blood?",
    "option1": "Lymphocytes",
    "option2": "Monocytes",
    "option3": "Erythrocytes",
    "option4": "Blood Platelets",
    "answer": "Lymphocytes"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "The fungal derivative used in the treatment of tuberculosis is",
    "option1": "Anacin",
    "option2": "Aspirin",
    "option3": "Streptomycin",
    "option4": "Tetracycline",
    "answer": "Streptomycin"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "How many pairs of spinal nerves are present in the human body?",
    "option1": 28,
    "option2": 31,
    "option3": 35,
    "option4": 42,
    "answer": 31
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What cause malaria and sleeping sickness?",
    "option1": "Bacteria",
    "option2": "Viruses",
    "option3": "Protozoans",
    "option4": "None of these",
    "answer": "Protozoans"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Number of bones in human body is",
    "option1": 220,
    "option2": 292,
    "option3": 302,
    "option4": 206,
    "answer": 206
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following organism is iteroparous?",
    "option1": "Pacific Salmon Fish",
    "option2": "Virus",
    "option3": "Bacteria",
    "option4": "Human",
    "answer": "Human"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "The science related to the study of the composition of tissues is called",
    "option1": "Cytology",
    "option2": "Mycology",
    "option3": "Histology",
    "option4": "Anatomy",
    "answer": "Histology"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "A hereditary disease which progressively damages muscle fibres and eventually destroys them is",
    "option1": "Muscular Dystrophy",
    "option2": "Hepatitis",
    "option3": "Meningitis",
    "option4": "None of these",
    "answer": "Muscular Dystrophy"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "A branch of science dealing with the study of teeth is",
    "option1": "Gerontology",
    "option2": "Odontology",
    "option3": "Entomology",
    "option4": "Ornithology",
    "answer": "Odontology"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "The phenomenon of summer sleep by animals is called",
    "option1": "Hibernation",
    "option2": "Aestivation",
    "option3": "Laziness",
    "option4": "Lethargy",
    "answer": "Aestivation"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The phenomenon of winter sleep by animals is called",
    "option1": "Hibernation",
    "option2": "Aestivation",
    "option3": "Laziness",
    "option4": "Lethargy",
    "answer": "Hibernation"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Night blindness is caused due to deficiency of Vitamin",
    "option1": "A",
    "option2": "B",
    "option3": "E",
    "option4": "K",
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Skeleton of sponges is produced by",
    "option1": "Sclerocytes",
    "option2": "Thescocytes",
    "option3": "Pinacocytes",
    "option4": "Choanocytes",
    "answer": "Sclerocytes"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Sweating on palm and sole due to psychic stimuli is called",
    "option1": "Bradykinin",
    "option2": "Blushing",
    "option3": "Cold Sweat",
    "option4": "None of these",
    "answer": "Cold Sweat"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "In scorpion, poison is present in the",
    "option1": "Leg",
    "option2": "Hand",
    "option3": "Sting",
    "option4": "Mouth",
    "answer": "Sting"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What is the study of the basic principals, procedures, and rules of classification?",
    "option1": "Nomenclature",
    "option2": "Systematics",
    "option3": "Taxonomy",
    "option4": "Classification",
    "answer": "Taxonomy"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Since the 1700's, the naming system is a",
    "option1": "Monomial",
    "option2": "Binomial",
    "option3": "Trinomial",
    "option4": "Decanomial",
    "answer": "Binomial"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Birds excrete nitrogenous waste in the form of",
    "option1": "Urea",
    "option2": "Ammonia",
    "option3": "Fatty Acid",
    "option4": "Uric Acid",
    "answer": "Uric Acid"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Medulla oblongata is called",
    "option1": "Piameter",
    "option2": "Durameter",
    "option3": "Vital Knot",
    "option4": "Pons Varolii",
    "answer": "Vital Knot"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Bleeding of gums is one of the symptoms of",
    "option1": "Beri Beri",
    "option2": "Scurvy",
    "option3": "Sterility",
    "option4": "Pellagra",
    "answer": "Scurvy"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Rabies is transmitted by",
    "option1": "Bugs",
    "option2": "Flies",
    "option3": "Dogs",
    "option4": "Cats",
    "answer": "Dogs"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "The outer convex region of kidney is called",
    "option1": "Cortex",
    "option2": "Calyces",
    "option3": "Nephron",
    "option4": "Pelvis",
    "answer": "Cortex"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "The escape of haemoglobin from RBC is known as",
    "option1": "Clotting",
    "option2": "Thermolysis",
    "option3": "Anaemia",
    "option4": "Haemorrhage",
    "answer": "Thermolysis"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "The color of inner part of brain",
    "option1": "Red",
    "option2": "Blue",
    "option3": "Green",
    "option4": "White",
    "answer": "White"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "The largest living animals belong to the group of",
    "option1": "Fishes",
    "option2": "Birds",
    "option3": "Invertebrates",
    "option4": "Mammals",
    "answer": "Mammals"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Dialysis is given to a man having problems in",
    "option1": "Phosphorus",
    "option2": "Magnesium",
    "option3": "Calcium",
    "option4": "Iron",
    "answer": "Iron"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Which among the following helps in circulation of blood?",
    "option1": "Lymphocytes",
    "option2": "Monocytes",
    "option3": "Arythrocytes",
    "option4": "Blood Platelets",
    "answer": "Lymphocytes"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Which among the following is a large spectrum Antibiotic?",
    "option1": "Penicillin",
    "option2": "Paracetamol",
    "option3": "Ampicillin",
    "option4": "Chloramphenicol",
    "answer": "Ampicillin"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Our bones and teeth are generally made of",
    "option1": "Hydrolith",
    "option2": "Chloropetite",
    "option3": "Fluoropetite",
    "option4": "Tricalcium phosphate",
    "answer": "Tricalcium phosphate"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "The fungal derivative used in the treatment of tuberculosis is",
    "option1": "Anacin",
    "option2": "Streptomycin",
    "option3": "Aspirin",
    "option4": "Tetracycline",
    "answer": "Streptomycin"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Which of the following is also called Jelly Fish?",
    "option1": "Hydra",
    "option2": "Aurelia",
    "option3": "Physelia",
    "option4": "Matrideam",
    "answer": "Aurelia"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Which of the following disease is related to Vitamin B3?",
    "option1": "Pellagra",
    "option2": "Night blindness",
    "option3": "Rickets",
    "option4": "Beri Beri",
    "answer": "Pellagra"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Which one among the following is not a living fossil?",
    "option1": "Diplodocus",
    "option2": "Elephant Shrew",
    "option3": "Stromatolite",
    "option4": "Ginkgo",
    "answer": "Diplodocus"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Which one of the following genetic diseases is sex linked?",
    "option1": "Cystic fibrosis",
    "option2": "Haemophilia",
    "option3": "Tay-Sachs Disease",
    "option4": "None of these",
    "answer": "Haemophilia"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Which of the following does not have blood but undergoes respiration?",
    "option1": "Kangaroo",
    "option2": "Cockroach",
    "option3": "Hydra",
    "option4": "Snail",
    "answer": "Hydra"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "The scientist who firstly explained about the blood circulation",
    "option1": "Ronald Ross",
    "option2": "J.G. Mendel",
    "option3": "William Harvey",
    "option4": "Leeuwenhoek",
    "answer": "William Harvey"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "The study of bones is done under the branch of science called",
    "option1": "Geology",
    "option2": "Seromology",
    "option3": "Orology",
    "option4": "Osteology",
    "answer": "Osteology"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Which of the following does not have any enzymes in its cells?",
    "option1": "Lichen",
    "option2": "Virus",
    "option3": "Bacteria",
    "option4": "Algae",
    "answer": "Virus"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "In which organ of the human body are the lymphocytes formed?",
    "option1": "Liver",
    "option2": "Bone Marrow",
    "option3": "Spleen",
    "option4": "Pancreas",
    "answer": "Bone Marrow"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Which of the following hormones contains Iodine?",
    "option1": "Testosterone",
    "option2": "Adrenaline",
    "option3": "Thyroxine",
    "option4": "Insulin",
    "answer": "Insulin"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "AIDS is caused by",
    "option1": "Helminth",
    "option2": "Bacteria",
    "option3": "Fungus",
    "option4": "Virus",
    "answer": "Virus"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Which of the following is a substance available in small quantity in the sea and administered in a certain deficiency disease?",
    "option1": "Fluorine",
    "option2": "Iodine",
    "option3": "Iron",
    "option4": "Vitamin A",
    "answer": "Iodine"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "The mad cow disease is caused by",
    "option1": "Virus",
    "option2": "Fungus",
    "option3": "Prion",
    "option4": "Bacteria",
    "answer": "Prion"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Which one of the following disease is not caused by virus?",
    "option1": "Rabies",
    "option2": "Polio",
    "option3": "Diphtheria",
    "option4": "Small Pox",
    "answer": "Diphtheria"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "What is the second fastest land animal in the world?",
    "option1": "Springbuk",
    "option2": "Leopard",
    "option3": "Pronghorn",
    "option4": "Jackrabbit",
    "answer": "Pronghorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Which is the next animal in 'Big five' of Africa after lion, leopard, rhino and elephant?",
    "option1": "Cape Buffalo",
    "option2": "Hartebeest",
    "option3": "Spotted Hyena",
    "option4": "Warthog",
    "answer": "Cape Buffalo"
  }
]